<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-17T00:35:23-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">josh shi</title><subtitle>josh shi cool man funny website haha</subtitle><entry><title type="html">“What Design Means to Me” by Karel Martens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/15/what-design-means-to-me-by-karel-martens.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“What Design Means to Me” by Karel Martens" /><published>2018-01-15T00:34:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-15T00:34:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/15/what-design-means-to-me-by-karel-martens</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/15/what-design-means-to-me-by-karel-martens.html">&lt;p&gt;Following up yesterday’s statement by designer Weiyi Li, this brief essay comes from one of her teachers at Yale, graphic designer Karel Martens. Here, Martens discusses how he has come to understand the role of design not only as a craft or a profession, but as an extension of himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His take on design is relatively straightforward. Having been brought up in the dogma of Modernism and (at time of writing) now living and designing during a time when those ideals were being so utterly rejected, he draws a middle ground between a completely functional view of design, where the designer’s opinions and beliefs are left out, and a completely expressive view of design, often at the expense of readability: what he refers to as “form about form.” He instead asks for a “form that values content and has respect for the receiver of the message.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to keep in mind what was going on in graphic design at the time. Martens wrote this in 1990, in the middle of what would later become know as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.printmag.com/typography/legibility-wars-translation-typography/&quot;&gt;“The Legibility Wars of the ‘80s and ‘90s.”&lt;/a&gt;, a period in graphic design history when new technology and changing attitudes among younger designers resulted in a clash between the old and new guard. Older designers were mostly still rooted in the Modernist, Swiss styles while younger designers were excited to explore everything that new technology made possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1984, Rudy VanderLans started publishing &lt;em&gt;Emigre&lt;/em&gt;, a graphic design magazine which was visually very divisive among designers for its exploration of eclectic type and bold, disruptive typography. Other publications, many founded by young students, started to eschew old rules of readability for the sake of expression. The second installment of the critical graphic design essay series, &lt;em&gt;Looking Closer 2&lt;/em&gt;, was published in 1997 and contains many essays on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear to see that this essay then is a product of the times, when this sort of debate was a hot topic in the design community. But I think what’s interesting about this is his rejection of content as having some sort of precedence over form. He says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The content of the message has to come over, but the way in which this happens—the melody—is important, not least because in itself it carries communicative value. It is through form that content comes to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a sentiment which has more recently been echoed by Michael Rock in his essay, &lt;a href=&quot;https://2x4.org/ideas/2/fuck-content/&quot;&gt;“Fuck Content”&lt;/a&gt; and his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/videos/2016-06-02/bloomberg-businessweek-design-2016-michael-rock&quot;&gt;opening keynote&lt;/a&gt; to Bloomberg Businessweek Design 2016, in which he advocates for the legitimacy of design in its own right. In Rock’s words, design makes things coherent. Things in the world become real by design—ideas are given form, ideologies given authority, humans given identity. Design is crucial to our understanding of the world and ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Following up yesterday’s statement by designer Weiyi Li, this brief essay comes from one of her teachers at Yale, graphic designer Karel Martens. Here, Martens discusses how he has come to understand the role of design not only as a craft or a profession, but as an extension of himself.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Function as Narrative” by Weiyi Li</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/13/function-as-narrative-by-weiyi-li.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Function as Narrative” by Weiyi Li" /><published>2018-01-13T15:39:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-13T15:39:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/13/function-as-narrative-by-weiyi-li</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/13/function-as-narrative-by-weiyi-li.html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing the discussion that’s been going on with these &lt;a href=&quot;http://joshshi.com/2018/01/12/specific-objects-by-donald-judd.html&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://joshshi.com/2018/01/10/thing-theory-by-bill-brown.html&quot;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; essays on objects is “Function as Narrative,” a statement written by designed &lt;a href=&quot;http://weiyi.li&quot;&gt;Weiyi Li&lt;/a&gt; during her time as a MFA student at Yale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Li’s essay discusses some work she’s done to explore the theme of function as narrative, or this idea that “FUNCTION is the projection of human needs on objects… Objects with FUNCTION indicate a possibility of something to happen. FUNCTION leads to a potential story, thus FUNCTION is indeed a narrative.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, of course, is not a novel concept. Even among the most cookie-cutter design-thinking processes, narrative is stressed as a tool to develop empathy and spot pain points for users, often through the use of things like personas and journey maps. What makes Li’s objects different from products of design thinking process, however, is how &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; they are. The narratives discussed in these projects do not necessarily address a user’s goal or problem but rather explore the relationships between the users and their products. These narratives are deeply personal rather than practical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of her projects is a take on the ring sizer, a piece of plastic with circles of varying sizes cut out to help people find the circumference of their fingers. She takes this idea and creates a new “template,” but instead of many circles intended to measure the same part of her body, she includes many circles, each of which maps to a different part. For example, there is the standard circle for finger size, as well as toes, nipples, tongue, and eyelashes. The template, although it takes a very similar form to the original, now bears a very different narrative. This new object is an exploration in biometrics, and as such becomes almost a form of identification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, there’s also a certain role reversal that occurs in the relationship between Li and the template. Originally, the ring sizer, with its standardized units of measurements, was mass-produced and provided to help users conform to a certain system. This gets turned on its head once the template becomes a record rather than a point of comparison. The many to many relation between object and user now becomes one to one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Li’s work in this statement also explore themes of use/misuse and the fluidity of such narratives. She draws on the work of one of her teachers, designer Karel Martens, who used ready-made objects as stamps, and discusses her “ring collection.” This collection comprises objects which were not designed to be rings but could be worn on the finger and considered a ring (i.e. they consist of some time of embellishment or ornament attached to a circular shape which could be worn on a finger).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there are interesting connections between this and Bill Brown’s “Thing Theory.” Many of the items in this collection are unrecognizable to me, so to me they register as things rather than objects. This means that they not only lose their original identity, but also that they readily accept any new identity which is prescribed to them. Li labels and sells these items as rings, so they become rings only because we do not know them to be anything else. As she describes it, “I was trying to tell a lie one thousand times to make it true.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Continuing the discussion that’s been going on with these past few essays on objects is “Function as Narrative,” a statement written by designed Weiyi Li during her time as a MFA student at Yale.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Specific Objects” by Donald Judd</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/11/specific-objects-by-donald-judd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Specific Objects” by Donald Judd" /><published>2018-01-11T22:30:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-11T22:30:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/11/specific-objects-by-donald-judd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/11/specific-objects-by-donald-judd.html">&lt;p&gt;A lot has been said about this particular essay, and for good reason. It serves as Donald Judd’s observations (as I understand it, the text is often misinterpreted as a manifesto for his specific branch of minimalist, Modernist art rather than a description) of the work he has found interesting, these pieces which are “neither painting nor sculpture.” It’s difficult to understand what he means without seeing such a work, so here is an image of one of Judd’s pieces, &lt;em&gt;Untitled&lt;/em&gt;, created four years after the publication of “Specific Objects: “&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.guggenheim.org/wp-content/uploads/1969/01/91.3713_ph_web.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judd's *Untitled*&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Judd's &lt;em&gt;Untitled&lt;/em&gt;, 1969&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True to its description, it bears few to no resemblance to painting or sculpture. It shrugs off the hand of the artist, the interpretation of the viewer, the spatiality suggested by a painting’s frame. It sits there, in all three-dimensions, and just commands your attention. As Judd says,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Three dimensions are real space. That gets rid of the problem of illusionism and of literal space, space in and around marks and colors - which is riddance of one of the salient and most objectionable relics of European art. The several limits of painting are no longer present. A work can be as powerful as it can be thought to be. Actual space is intrinsically more powerful and specific than paint on a flat surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think one of the things that really stood out to me about this essay was the lucidity with which Judd speaks about the media on which he and his fellow artists work. It’s very cool to hear a discussion on the limitations of a medium like painting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Almost all paintings are spatial in one way or another. Yves Klein’s blue paintings are the only ones that are unspatial, and there is little that is nearly unspatial, mainly Stella’s work. It’s possible that not much can be done with both an upright rectangular plane and an absence of space. Anything on a surface has space behind it. Two colors on the same surface almost always lie on different depths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Except for a complete and unvaried field of color or marks, anything spaced in a rectangle and on a plane suggests something in and on something else, something in its surround, which suggests an object or figure in its space, in which these are clearer instances of a similar world - that’s the main purpose of painting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Judd’s purpose in naming these attributes is to thoroughly subvert them in order to challenge traditional understandings of form and to create new, interesting work. “The disinterest in painting and sculpture is a disinterest in doing it again,” he says, “not in it as it is being done.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of other &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artuner.com/insight/judd-andre-deshayes-concept-specific-objects/&quot;&gt;pieces&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guggenheim.org/artwork/1741&quot;&gt;out there&lt;/a&gt; written by people more knowledgable about art history than myself, so I won’t use this post to discuss Judd’s impact on art history. Instead, I think it would be interesting to refer back to another essay I read previously for this series, Bill Brown’s “Thing Theory.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In “Thing Theory,” Brown discusses an idea of how objects that we are familiar with become things. Designers, somewhat obviously, make objects. Any object which is designed to perform a function does so by the will of its creator. When that object breaks down, becomes obsolete, or otherwise is no longer viewed as being able to serve that function, it loses its status as an object and becomes a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certain things are things to some people and not to others. A child looking at a typewriter may not recognize it or understand it as a tool for writing. To the child, the typewriter is a thing. To an older person who may have used a typewriter in the past, it is still recognized as an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to see then that even though these works being described to us as referred to as “specific objects,” they fall very much in line with Brown’s definition of things. In fact, both essays mention the work of Claes Oldenburg, in reference to his three-dimensional pieces of scaled-up objects, like a clothespin or typewriter eraser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what makes these specific objects especially powerful, aside from Judd’s point on the power of three-dimensional space, is their immediate status as things. As we view each thing in its entirety, we are immediately confronted with its thing-ness. As opposed to traditional art (e.g. a painting depicting a scene, a statue of a person), where we may first attempt to interpret or understand it, this thing confronts us with its cold indifference and asks us to think about our relationships not only with the object but also with art.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">A lot has been said about this particular essay, and for good reason. It serves as Donald Judd’s observations (as I understand it, the text is often misinterpreted as a manifesto for his specific branch of minimalist, Modernist art rather than a description) of the work he has found interesting, these pieces which are “neither painting nor sculpture.” It’s difficult to understand what he means without seeing such a work, so here is an image of one of Judd’s pieces, Untitled, created four years after the publication of “Specific Objects: “</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“What Theory is Not, Theorizing Is” by Karl Weick</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/10/what-theory-is-not-theorizing-is-by-karl-weick.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“What Theory is Not, Theorizing Is” by Karl Weick" /><published>2018-01-10T21:51:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-10T21:51:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/10/what-theory-is-not-theorizing-is-by-karl-weick</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/10/what-theory-is-not-theorizing-is-by-karl-weick.html">&lt;p&gt;Theories are strange things. They’re often so comfortable that we forget they’re at best approximations. They are, by definition, abstractions over a  a real thing. This is not to say that they’re fragile or unreliable—theories are developed to be resilient, and the process through which theories are formed (i.e. theorizing) is itself rigorous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both theory and theorizing are the topics of Karl Weick’s essay, “What Theory Is &lt;em&gt;Not&lt;/em&gt;, Theorizing &lt;em&gt;Is&lt;/em&gt;,” a response to an essay entitled “What Theory is Not” by Robert Sutton and Barry Staw (all three are researchers in organizational studies). The original essay demarcated a line between papers that contain theory and papers that do not, and named five elements that were often used by authors in place of theory (i.e. references, data, variables, diagrams, and hypotheses). Sutton and Staw bring this issue to light because they describe observing a rash of authors submitting papers with little to no theory simply because journals require strong theory, the effect of which is a weakening of the standards of theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weick’s response to this is not a counterargument but rather a tangential discussion of the act of theorizing, the practice that leads to theory. He describes some of the difficulties that novice theorists might have in identifying which “which of their efforts are theory and which are not. This difficulty arises,” he goes on to say, “because theory work can take a variety of forms, because theory itself is a continuum, and because most verbally expressed theory leaves tacit some key portions of the originating insight.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “originating insight” can consist of any number of activities which led to the development of the theory. And while those activities themselves may not be eligible to be called theories, their existence is necessary for a theory to exist. Whereas a paper without theory may be labeled as having an insufficient contribution, a theory without any rigor or grounding is just as pointless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Theories are strange things. They’re often so comfortable that we forget they’re at best approximations. They are, by definition, abstractions over a a real thing. This is not to say that they’re fragile or unreliable—theories are developed to be resilient, and the process through which theories are formed (i.e. theorizing) is itself rigorous.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Thing Theory” by Bill Brown</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/09/thing-theory-by-bill-brown.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Thing Theory” by Bill Brown" /><published>2018-01-09T23:14:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-09T23:14:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/09/thing-theory-by-bill-brown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/09/thing-theory-by-bill-brown.html">&lt;p&gt;Think about how easy it is to take objects for granted. You probably have many things literally within arm’s reach at all times—your phone, a wallet, maybe a pair of earbuds. We interact with and use objects every day, some more often than others, some with more ease than others, but always with intention. After all, these objects only make sense in the context of a &lt;em&gt;subject&lt;/em&gt;, usually us, who bestows upon them a purpose. But what happens when this purpose is lost? What about when an object breaks, falls into obsolescence, or is no longer understood? This, and more, is the study of Bill Brown’s essay, “Thing Theory,” in which he provides a way of thinking about the relationships between objects and things as well as our relationships to both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a point of clarification, when Brown talks about “things” here he is meaning exactly what it sounds like: that which we refer to when we say, “hand me that thing over there” or, “what’s that thing you showed me last night?” Things represent that which lies just beyond our grasp. They’re something we know exists and can describe, perhaps even define, but cannot name. As Brown describes it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The word designates the concrete yet ambiguous within the everyday: “Put it by that green thing in the hall.” It functions to overcome the loss of other words or as a place holder for some future specifying operation: “I need that thing you use to get at things between your teeth.” It designates an amorphous characteristic or a frankly irresolvable enigma: “There’s a thing about that poem that I’ll never get.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In understanding the thing then we start to understand our relationships with objects. An object loses its identity and becomes a thing when it no longer fits our model of what that object should be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We begin to confront the thingness of objects when they stop working for us: when the drill breaks, when the car stalls, when the windows get filthy, when their flow within the circuits of production and distribution, consumption and exhibition, has been arrested, however momentarily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus this transition from object to thing becomes less about the thing itself. After all, the thing is still the thing; a broken drill is still made of all the same atoms as a working one, give or take a few. What becomes more clear is our relation to the object. When a drill breaks, it’s no longer a drill to us because it cannot perform the function for which it was named.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are clear connections between these ideas and Modernist design principles. As Louis Sullivan’s maxim goes, “form follows function.” What, then, happens to the form when the function can no longer be fulfilled?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few other Modernists played with the idea of the thing as well. Brown mentions in his essay the work of Surrealists, who frequently removed objects from their comfortable, functional context and turned them into things: Salvador Dali dreamed of a manuscript written in white ink on a brand-new Rolls Royce; André Breton dreamed of finding “a book with a wooden statue of an Assyrian gnome as its spine, and with pages made of black wool” at a flea market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a similar stark awareness of the object that comes from looking at René Magritte’s &lt;em&gt;The Treachery of Images&lt;/em&gt;. The painting, which depicts a pipe and displays the words “Ceci n’est pas une pipe.” (“this is not a pipe”), depicts an object but it is not the object. As Alfred Korzybski said, “the word is not the thing.” I’m also reminded of the work of Giorgio de Chirico, an artist whose work influenced the surrealist movement greatly and revolved around mysterious, ominous scenes. His paintings contained many things, but even the objects you might be able to identify were placed outside their normal context. These objects, now placed in a strange setting with no suggestion as to why it would be there or how it came to be, defy normal understanding and lose any associations with a subject—they can now be understood as things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/1f/Giorgio_de_Chirico%2C_1914-15%2C_Le_mauvais_génie_d’un_roi_%28The_Evil_Genius_of_a_King%29%2C_oil_on_canvas%2C_61_×_50.2_cm%2C_Museum_of_Modern_Art%2C_New_York.jpg/1280px-Giorgio_de_Chirico%2C_1914-15%2C_Le_mauvais_génie_d’un_roi_%28The_Evil_Genius_of_a_King%29%2C_oil_on_canvas%2C_61_×_50.2_cm%2C_Museum_of_Modern_Art%2C_New_York.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chirico's *Le mauvais génie d'un roi (The Evil Genius of a King)*&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Chirico's &lt;em&gt;Le mauvais génie d'un roi (The Evil Genius of a King)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking more generally, I think one of the most interesting things Brown mentions is the role that things play in our lives. Since they no longer carry the burden of having to serve a purpose or perform a task, we accept things for what they are—we don’t judge them for their usefulness. There’s a piece called &lt;em&gt;Typewriter Eraser, Scale X&lt;/em&gt;,  a large-scale sculpture of a typewriter eraser by American sculptor Claes Oldenburg that sits in the sculpture garden at the National Gallery of Art. Brown describes the different experiences of people who come across the sculpture:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The pleasure of looking at the people looking at the &lt;em&gt;Typewriter Eraser&lt;/em&gt;, amused by its monumentality, is inseparable from the pleasure of listening to the child who, befuddled by an anachronistic object she never knew, pleads: “What is that thing supposed to be?” What is this disk with the brush sticking out of it? What was a typewriter? How did that form ever function? The plea expresses the power of this particular work to dramatize a generational divide and to stage (to melodramatize, even) the question of obsolescence. While the “timeless” objects in the Oldenburg canon (fans and sinks) have gone limp, this abandoned object attains a new stature precisely because it has no life outside the boundary of art—no life, that is, within our everyday lives. Released from the bond of being equipment, sustained outside the irreversibility of technological history, the object becomes something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://etc.usf.edu/clippix/pix/typewriter-eraser-scale-x_medium.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oldenburg's *Typewriter Eraser, Scale X*&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Oldenburg's &lt;em&gt;Typewriter Eraser, Scale X&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Think about how easy it is to take objects for granted. You probably have many things literally within arm’s reach at all times—your phone, a wallet, maybe a pair of earbuds. We interact with and use objects every day, some more often than others, some with more ease than others, but always with intention. After all, these objects only make sense in the context of a subject, usually us, who bestows upon them a purpose. But what happens when this purpose is lost? What about when an object breaks, falls into obsolescence, or is no longer understood? This, and more, is the study of Bill Brown’s essay, “Thing Theory,” in which he provides a way of thinking about the relationships between objects and things as well as our relationships to both.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“The Creative Act” by Marcel Duchamp</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/08/the-creative-act-by-marcel-duchamp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“The Creative Act” by Marcel Duchamp" /><published>2018-01-08T17:39:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-08T17:39:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/08/the-creative-act-by-marcel-duchamp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/08/the-creative-act-by-marcel-duchamp.html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s a brief but interesting essay to think about by Marcel Duchamp in which he discusses the role of the artist and the spectator (viewers, critics, historians) in what he describes as “the two poles of creation” in the creative process. Near the beginning, he makes a rather bold assertion about the artist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To all appearances, the artist acts like a mediumistic being who, from the labyrinth beyond space and time, seeks his way out to a clearing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If we give the attributes of a medium to the artist, we must then deny him the state of consciousness on the esthetic plane about what he is doing or why he is doing it. All his decisions in the artistic execution of the work rest with pure intuition and cannot be translated into a self-analysis, spoken or written, or even thought out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He quotes a line from T.S. Eliot in an essay, “Tradition and the Individual Talent,” where Eliot says, “the more perfect the artist, the more completely separate in him will be the man who suffers and the mind which creates.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this definition of the artist is hard to swallow, that’s because it is. After all, it doesn’t really seem reasonable for a person to create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; significant without deliberation and intentionality. Following this definition, how could an artist ever produce art? Duchamp recognizes this dissonance and proceeds to talk about what he refers to as the “art coefficient,” the difference between what the author meant to create, what has actually been created, and how the viewer interprets the work (I’ve heard Elliot Earls describe this same concept as “slippage” in one of his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC_1qlsIrMnixjorbUg4k3RA/featured&quot;&gt;Studio Practice videos&lt;/a&gt;). Duchamp says the artist is not conscious of this difference. This is where the viewer comes in—the creative act does not end once the artist finishes a piece, but instead extends into the viewing, when a spectator completes the art coefficient (which until now is in its raw state, or &lt;em&gt;à l’état brut&lt;/em&gt;) by interpreting a work. It’s through this process that the spectator judges the piece (i.e. critiques) and transmutes the ideas of the artist into ideas of the viewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there’s a lot to unpack in this relatively short essay, but one of the things that I first began to think about was how prevalent the tenants of Modernism played into Duchamp’s ideas. An interesting omission from this essay is any acknowledgement of talent or skill in the creative process (in fact, the thought of an artist developing his or her skill or practicing a certain technique almost seems like it would go against his concept of an artist), and instead insisting that the ideal artist would act without awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Modernism diverges from previous understandings of art art. After all, that’s how art used to be made—if you wanted to paint a tree, you’d have to go out and study the leaves. If you wanted to paint a field, you’d have to go out and learn about perspective to capture the field. Here, however, we start to understand that art is no longer just about representing something tangible, but about being a conduit for the artist’s mind. The mind is the interesting part here, not the trees or the field. Art is a medium for communicating ideas, emotions, or anything else which escapes words. Artists must inexorably find some medium to transfer these ideas through, but it’s still possible to be mindful of the limitations that come from manifesting thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Postscript:&lt;/em&gt; After writing this response it occurred to me that there may be another profession which fits the bill for Duchamp’s ideal “unaware practitioner:” the athlete. In one of my favorite David Foster Wallace essays, “How Tracy Austin Broke My Heart,” DFW contemplates why we so often ridicule athletes for being unable to speak gracefully about their sport, often reciting what we view as clichés or trite, vacuous comments in interviews or in their memoirs. Perhaps, he says, the reason why these athletes speak this way (e.g. “just gotta keep your eye on the ball,” “we just have to play our best and work together”) because to them these phrases are comprehensive (in DFW’s words, “exhaustively descriptive”). These athletes are not only naturals, but they’ve also dedicated so much time to practicing and perfecting these movements that they’ve come to understand them as the truth, the whole truth, and nothing but the truth. They don’t think deeply or profoundly about these topics because to them there just isn’t anything to think—they just &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;. I think this fits perfectly with what Duchamp is searching for: a being who operates in a state of semi-consciousness, their body simply a canvas through which they practice their craft. As DFW states it, “those who receive and act out the gift of athletic genius must, perforce, be blind and dumb about it—and not because blindness and dumbness are the price of the gift, but because they are its essence.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Here’s a brief but interesting essay to think about by Marcel Duchamp in which he discusses the role of the artist and the spectator (viewers, critics, historians) in what he describes as “the two poles of creation” in the creative process. Near the beginning, he makes a rather bold assertion about the artist:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Art Criticism” by Clement Greenberg</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/06/art-criticism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Art Criticism” by Clement Greenberg" /><published>2018-01-06T12:51:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-06T12:51:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/06/art-criticism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/06/art-criticism.html">&lt;p&gt;“Art Criticism” is a short and straightforward piece by Clement Greenberg in which he reminds us what art criticism is and isn’t in the face of changing attitudes and conceptions about art. If you’ve read Greenberg’s “Avant-Garde and Kitsch” or “Modernist Painting,” you’ll know that he was kept very busy during the early twentieth century with thinking about how different parts of the art world had to change due to the rise of Modernism. “Art Criticism” is one such example in which Greenberg explores in very simple terms the purpose behind criticism, aesthetics, and value judgments—what most of us think of as “taste.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this essay, Greenberg essentially says that because Modernism had come and broken everyone’s previous understandings and ideas about art, critics of his time started believing that the traditional ways of evaluating art (i.e. aesthetics) had been invalidated as well. They then began to pass other things off as criticism, like description, analysis, or interpretation. They started to talk &lt;em&gt;around&lt;/em&gt; the piece rather than &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; it, and would discuss things like the social/political/economic contexts of its making. But while these things are interesting and do provide value in our understanding of a piece, Greenberg plainly says that they are not criticism (although things like description, analysis and interpretation do carry with them implicit value judgments, they are not meant to communicate or justify those judgments). Everyone, when they experience a work of art, has some reaction to it and makes some value judgment on it, whether implicit or explicit. However, not everyone is able to verbalize their judgments (and not everyone is even fully conscious of their judgments). Critics, however, are obligated to communicate their value judgments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, the judgment is the most difficult part of art criticism. It’s easy to sound knowledgable or authoritative about something when you’re stating facts. To make a judgment, however, to say that a work is &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt;, is hard. These subjective measures open the door for disagreement, and it’s hard to justify why you like or dislike something (it also makes it very easy for you to be on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=9D02E2D71131E233A2575BC0A9669D946096D6CF&amp;amp;mcubz=3&quot;&gt;wrong side of history&lt;/a&gt;). Especially during a time like the early 1900s when everything about art seemed to be changing so quickly, it would be easy to find solace in facts rather than judgments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These difficulties, however, are what make art criticism meaningful and worthwhile. To discuss and write about art as art, not as a document of history or philosophy, is to recognize our relationship with it and the effect it can have on us. The role of the critic is then to put into words his or her experience with a given piece of art, and it is through that criticism that we not only come to understand another person’s perspective, but can also understand our own reactions more deeply. But in order to do this, we must be honest and direct with ourselves about what we feel and how we evaluate our experience. We can only truly appreciate art when we take it for what it is.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">“Art Criticism” is a short and straightforward piece by Clement Greenberg in which he reminds us what art criticism is and isn’t in the face of changing attitudes and conceptions about art. If you’ve read Greenberg’s “Avant-Garde and Kitsch” or “Modernist Painting,” you’ll know that he was kept very busy during the early twentieth century with thinking about how different parts of the art world had to change due to the rise of Modernism. “Art Criticism” is one such example in which Greenberg explores in very simple terms the purpose behind criticism, aesthetics, and value judgments—what most of us think of as “taste.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Trash, Art, and the Movies” by Pauline Kael</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/02/trash-art-and-the-movies-by-pauline-kael.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Trash, Art, and the Movies” by Pauline Kael" /><published>2018-01-02T20:49:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-02T20:49:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/02/trash-art-and-the-movies-by-pauline-kael</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/02/trash-art-and-the-movies-by-pauline-kael.html">&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know who Pauline Kael was, I recommend giving her &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pauline_Kael&quot;&gt;Wikipedia page&lt;/a&gt; a quick pass. She was and continues to be an incredibly divisive figure, and during her 23-year tenure at the &lt;em&gt;New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;, she established herself as one of the influential voices of film criticism to date. Her opinions on movies often went contrary to those of her contemporaries and the general public (for instance, she panned &lt;em&gt;The Sound of Music&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;West Side Story&lt;/em&gt; while praising films like &lt;em&gt;The Warriors&lt;/em&gt;), and she regularly butted heads with both her colleagues at the &lt;em&gt;New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; as well as people in the movie industry. Roger Ebert &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rogerebert.com/rogers-journal/knocked-up-at-the-movies&quot;&gt;said of her&lt;/a&gt;, “Pauline had no theory, no rules, no guidelines, no objective standards. You couldn’t apply her ‘approach’ to a film. With her it was all personal.” While I agree it’s clear that films were deeply personal to her, I would argue that she did have rules, theory, and guidelines behind her opinions. They just might not be what we expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Movies are probably the second-easiest media after television to consume. When you watch a movie in a theater, the screen is the only thing you see, the theater speakers the only thing you hear. You don’t so much give it your attention as it is demanded from you, and in return it saturates your senses. This, Kael says, makes movies “the most total and encompassing art form we have,” where “[our] reactions can seem the most personal and, maybe the most important, imaginable.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But movies can also be (and to be fair, it’s likely that the majority of movies are) utter trash, i.e. not good.” And “good” means a specific thing to Kael: “a good movie can take you out of your dull funk and the hopelessness that so often goes with slipping into a theatre; a good movie can make you feel alive again, in contact, not just lost in another city. Good movies make you care, make you believe in possibilities again.” Good movies provide escapism. They make use of their inherent totality and immerse their viewers to make them feel something. This definition of “goodness” seems very simple, but the way it’s achieved can be very complex. After all, movies require the careful orchestration of moving picture and sound, and the amount and diversity of work that goes into producing one makes it near-impossible for one person (e.g. the director) to have control over it all. But because of this, movies can become good, or even ascend to become “art,” in any number of ways. 
One of the most interesting parts of this essay is the ramifications of how Kael interprets movie art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Movie art is not the opposite of what we have always enjoyed in movies, it is not to be found in a return to that official high culture, it is what we have always found good in movies only more so. It’s the subversive gesture carried further, the moments of excitement sustained longer and extended into new meanings.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, for a movie to be art it must make us feel the things we felt in good movies, but in new ways. It requires a sort of novelty, an addition onto our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This suggests to me that there are two levels of art. There is art on the personal level, where a movie provides us as individuals a new way of seeing or understanding the world. There’s also, for lack of a better word, something of a “cultural” art, the contribution that a movie makes not to a single person but to a larger dialogue around film as a practice. But it’s the personal art that makes us fall in love with the movies, when we watch a movie and feel like we see a part of ourselves that we always knew was there but could never quite articulate, the understanding that someone else out there must feel that same thing too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The personal understanding of movies as art also leads Kael to express that our definitions of art are malleable. This explains why Ebert also said of her, “She’s accused of being inconsistent and contradicting herself. Directors would fall in and out of favor. With her there was no possibility of inconsistency, because she always wrote about what she felt right now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of a sudden, it becomes clear why Kael was so unconcerned with falling in line with her fellow critics, why her writing style is so raw and unfiltered, why she fought so hard for her opinions to be printed in their unedited and uncut form. If the point of a good movie is to show you something new, how could anyone else do that for you? No two viewings are the same, not even by the same person. There’s no use in trying to coming to agreement on two inherently different opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t mean that it’s not valuable to have critics or opinions at all, however. Critics provide invaluable contributions to the ongoing discourse around art. Their role is not to prescribe viewpoints, but to further expand the impact of a work itself and how it changes the way we understand ourselves and our world. Pauline Kael doesn’t care about whether we agree with her because her reviews are not persuasive arguments. They’re a documentation of her experience, not something we should try to match but something we should accept. As long as her work is used as the starting point for further conversations on movies, she has done her job. She’s not looking to project her views onto anyone else. Instead, we should use her writing to keep us thinking about our own relationships with movies, both trash and art.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">If you don’t know who Pauline Kael was, I recommend giving her Wikipedia page a quick pass. She was and continues to be an incredibly divisive figure, and during her 23-year tenure at the New Yorker, she established herself as one of the influential voices of film criticism to date. Her opinions on movies often went contrary to those of her contemporaries and the general public (for instance, she panned The Sound of Music, 2001: A Space Odyssey, and West Side Story while praising films like The Warriors), and she regularly butted heads with both her colleagues at the New Yorker as well as people in the movie industry. Roger Ebert said of her, “Pauline had no theory, no rules, no guidelines, no objective standards. You couldn’t apply her ‘approach’ to a film. With her it was all personal.” While I agree it’s clear that films were deeply personal to her, I would argue that she did have rules, theory, and guidelines behind her opinions. They just might not be what we expect.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">200 Essays</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/01/200-essays.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="200 Essays" /><published>2018-01-01T20:51:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T20:51:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/01/200-essays</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/01/200-essays.html">&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Attempting to read 200 essays and write 200 responses in 52 weeks. Find links to the essays &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1TV0BHvKXcsAeVzIfUON7zVkkmC_gkMfu3ufNPSqv6ds/edit?usp=sharing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unfollowjoshshi&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt; at me with suggestions (I need them).&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;See the posts below:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ol reversed=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    
        
            &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/01/15/what-design-means-to-me-by-karel-martens.html&quot;&gt;“What Design Means to Me” by Karel Martens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;January 15, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        
    
        
            &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/01/13/function-as-narrative-by-weiyi-li.html&quot;&gt;“Function as Narrative” by Weiyi Li&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;January 13, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        
    
        
            &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/01/11/specific-objects-by-donald-judd.html&quot;&gt;“Specific Objects” by Donald Judd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;January 11, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        
    
        
            &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/01/10/what-theory-is-not-theorizing-is-by-karl-weick.html&quot;&gt;“What Theory is Not, Theorizing Is” by Karl Weick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;January 10, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        
    
        
            &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/01/09/thing-theory-by-bill-brown.html&quot;&gt;“Thing Theory” by Bill Brown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;January 09, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        
    
        
            &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/01/08/the-creative-act-by-marcel-duchamp.html&quot;&gt;“The Creative Act” by Marcel Duchamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;January 08, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        
    
        
            &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/01/06/art-criticism.html&quot;&gt;“Art Criticism” by Clement Greenberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;January 06, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        
    
        
            &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/01/02/trash-art-and-the-movies-by-pauline-kael.html&quot;&gt;“Trash, Art, and the Movies” by Pauline Kael&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;January 02, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        
    
        
    
        
    
        
    
        
    
        
    
        
    
        
    
        
    
        
    
        
    
        
    
        
    
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Attempting to read 200 essays and write 200 responses in 52 weeks. Find links to the essays here. Tweet at me with suggestions (I need them). See the posts below: “What Design Means to Me” by Karel Martens January 15, 2018 “Function as Narrative” by Weiyi Li January 13, 2018 “Specific Objects” by Donald Judd January 11, 2018 “What Theory is Not, Theorizing Is” by Karl Weick January 10, 2018 “Thing Theory” by Bill Brown January 09, 2018 “The Creative Act” by Marcel Duchamp January 08, 2018 “Art Criticism” by Clement Greenberg January 06, 2018 “Trash, Art, and the Movies” by Pauline Kael January 02, 2018</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pyrus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/01/pyrus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pyrus" /><published>2018-01-01T17:32:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T17:32:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/01/pyrus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/01/pyrus.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past few quarters, my partner and I have been working on a research project focused on learning more about how we might design a collaborative coding game which helps novice computer science students develop their programming problem-solving skills. Our system is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pear&quot;&gt;Pyrus&lt;/a&gt; and the project is advised by Nell O’Rourke as part of a class called Design, Technology and Research. We recently submitted a paper to CHI 2018’s Student Research Competition, which focuses mostly on the design arguments for our system and our research contributions, but didn’t give us a chance to talk about some of the interesting technical challenges we faced. In this post, I’ll be going over how we handled one interesting technical hurdle by using Redux on the back-end to synchronize game state between a server and multiple clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-challenge&quot;&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provide some context, our system consists of a game which has a few standard game-like components, like a board and a deck of cards. In this game, players can take actions that mutate the state of the game across multiple components, e.g. drawing a card would pop a card off the top of the deck and push it onto the player’s hand. All these changes need to be propagated to all clients in real time and must be handled the same way to ensure that state changes are consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went back and forth on a few different methods for managing state, but we eventually realized that Redux was probably the best way to go for a couple of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;From a bit of digging online, we realized the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gamedev.stackexchange.com/questions/28820/how-do-i-sync-multiplayer-game-state-more-efficiently-than-full-state-updates&quot;&gt;typical&lt;/a&gt; way to keep state in sync between a server (the source of truth) and multiple clients in multiplayer games is to keep game state stored in a well-defined object model and &lt;em&gt;transmit all changes to game state as discrete events&lt;/em&gt;. This is pretty much Redux’s bread and butter.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using Redux on the back-end meant we could reuse much of our Redux code (e.g. actions, reducers, etc) on the front-end. Not only did it save us a lot of time from not having to write and maintain two sets of code that did the same thing, it also ensured that all actions were handled in exactly the same way between client and server.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We also needed the ability to intercept actions (e.g. in order to log them to a file) as they were dispatched. Redux allows you to do this really well through middleware.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was one sticking point: Redux is usually paired with a view library like React, and we weren’t able to find much information online about Redux being used on the server. This meant we had our work cut out for us as far as figuring out the best way to organize our application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our solution was to create a Game class which configures a Redux store in its constructor. Once a Game object is instantiated, its store becomes a member variable of that object, i.e. accessible through &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;this._store&lt;/code&gt;. This is what we use in place of traditional member variables to mutate the state of the game. Now any time we want to dispatch an action, we can simply call &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;this._store.dispatch(someActionCreator());&lt;/code&gt; from within the Game itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to do this is nice because it affords us a few benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We can expose a very simple API for interacting with the Game object. Outside code can call methods like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;game.start()&lt;/code&gt; instead of dispatching actions directly on a store themselves. (This abstraction carries over to all other objects, like our object for Deck or Board, since we construct those from the Game object we pass down the store to them too.) Additionally, if we ever need to fire multiple actions in sequence, we can just do that in a very straightforward way by simply writing out those dispatches one after another. No messing with thunks necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We can also keep all the business logic in the classes. There are a lot of checks in place to make sure that the game doesn’t end up in an invalid state, e.g. by allowing an inactive player to make a move or by executing an action that was actually illegal. Without a class to wrap all these checks around, they would probably all end up in the action. This object-oriented approach makes our code much easier to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This also provides an easy, reliable way to access member variables. Instead of keeping a laundry list of member variables that we mutate ourselves, we define getters which simply return the corresponding attribute via a call to  &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;this.store.getState().attrib&lt;/code&gt; within the class. This means we can avoid storing redundant information.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To take a look at how this works in practice, here’s some annotated example code (the following snippet is close to our implementation, but with some simplifications made for illustration purposes):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;createStore&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'redux'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;rootReducer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'../../reducers'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;gameStart&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'../../actions/game'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Board&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'../Board'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Game&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// the constructor initializes the Redux store and puts it&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// in a member variable of the Game object&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;constructor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;_store&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;createStore&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;rootReducer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// the &quot;board&quot; here is an object which encapsulates all&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// &quot;physical&quot; game components, e.g. players and the deck.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// all components get passed the store&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;board&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Board&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;_store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// this getter exposes a clean way for outside code to get &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// information from the Redux store without having to know&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// the actual layout of the store tree&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;status&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;_store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getState&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;game&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;status&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// returns whether the game successfully started&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// a check to make sure we don't end up in an invalid&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// state (i.e. starting the game when we shouldn't be.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;status&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'GAME_STATUS_INIT'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// to mutate state, we dispatch actions to our this._store&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;_store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;dispatch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;gameStart&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// we can easily dispatch multiple subsequent actions&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;board&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;players&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// like status above, board.players is actually a getter&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// that fetches an attribute from the state tree&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;player&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;board&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;players&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;];&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// bonus: the deck.draw function called here also&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// dispatches multiple actions to the store. since&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// we passed in the store in the board, which in turn&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// passes it to the deck, we can implement the draw &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// function in the deck and provide a much simpler&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// abstraction to use here&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;hand&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;board&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;deck&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;draw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;_store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;dispatch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;setPlayerHand&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;hand&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;player&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, using the same representation of game state on the server and the client made managing updates between clients really easy. We basically set up a WebSocket connection between the server and all the clients whenever a new client joins a game. On that connection, the server sends over the JSON representation of the current game state. Once that connection is established, the client will send a message to the server whenever the player performs an action (the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;JSON.stringify()&lt;/code&gt;’d Redux action). The server takes each message, parses it, does all the necessary checking, and handles that action. Attached to the store on the back-end is some custom middleware that intercepts every dispatched action and broadcasts it to all clients listening on that WebSocket connection. Those clients then receive those incoming WebSocket messages and dispatch each action on their own stores. This way, we guarantee that every state mutation the server applies is sent to the client as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an interesting problem to think through and it definitely took some time before we fell into a comfortable paradigm with it, but in the end I think it worked out really well. The ease of moving between the front- and back-end codebases, possible because that were both in Javascript they shared almost all their Redux code, was actually tremendously helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about abstracting some of the work we’ve done into a generalizable framework for writing multiplayer games in a full Javascript stack, but then a friend of mine recently pointed me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/boardgame.io&quot;&gt;boardgame.io&lt;/a&gt;. At time of writing it’s pretty new, but it provides a good layer of abstraction over all that state-management stuff and is conceptually very similar to what I outlined above. Check it out if you’re interested in a solution similar to what I’ve discussed that’s ready out-of-the-box.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Over the past few quarters, my partner and I have been working on a research project focused on learning more about how we might design a collaborative coding game which helps novice computer science students develop their programming problem-solving skills. Our system is called Pyrus and the project is advised by Nell O’Rourke as part of a class called Design, Technology and Research. We recently submitted a paper to CHI 2018’s Student Research Competition, which focuses mostly on the design arguments for our system and our research contributions, but didn’t give us a chance to talk about some of the interesting technical challenges we faced. In this post, I’ll be going over how we handled one interesting technical hurdle by using Redux on the back-end to synchronize game state between a server and multiple clients.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/pyrus/pyrus.png" /></entry></feed>