<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-08T23:55:12-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">josh shi</title><subtitle>josh shi cool man funny website haha</subtitle><entry><title type="html">“Construct a Perfect Pentagon” by Thomas De Monchaux</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/06/construct-a-perfect-pentagon-by-thomas-de-monchaux.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Construct a Perfect Pentagon” by Thomas De Monchaux" /><published>2018-02-06T23:52:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-02-06T23:52:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/06/construct-a-perfect-pentagon-by-thomas-de-monchaux</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/06/construct-a-perfect-pentagon-by-thomas-de-monchaux.html">&lt;p&gt;I had previously read another one of Thomas De Monchaux’s pieces, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nplusonemag.com/online-only/online-only/have-you-ever-had-an-intense-experience-of-mystical-communion-with-the-universe-life-god-etc/&quot;&gt;“Have You Ever Had an Intense Experience of Mystical Communion with the Universe, Life, God, etc?”&lt;/a&gt; (also published in &lt;em&gt;n+1&lt;/em&gt;) earlier last year. It was a review of a book on the life and work of architect Louis Kahn. That essay was one of the first essays I had read on architecture (I previously and foolishly tended to stay away from writings on architecture because I preferred to spend my time reading about graphic design), and the description of the field and the work made me realize exactly why designers today are so envious of the quality of dialogue architects and their critics are able to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard a lot of reasons (read: excuses) from designers (mostly graphic designers) as to why there isn’t a comparable body of criticism around design (mostly graphic design), and most of them naturally are comparisons between design and architecture. Design doesn’t have architecture’s age, its history, its patronage, etc, etc. You hear them so often you almost start to believe them. Then De Monchaux wrote “Construct a Perfect Pentagon,” which blows those discussions out of the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve read more than a few takes on Jesse Reed and Hamish Smyth’s Standards Manual practice, in which they revive and republish what amount to old brand guidelines which were assembled for laborers with no design training yet have achieved fetish object status among modern designers. What sets “Construct a Perfect Pentagon” apart from the rest is in its diligence, examining in detail not only a few of the actual manuals sold by Reed and Smyth but also their meanings—how they came to exist, what their construction meant for the institutions they represented, and how we as a country have now come to revere these old specification books and yet are content with the deterioration of our public works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s incredibly refreshing to read a piece of graphic design criticism from someone who is not a graphic designer (and the fact that it was published outside of a design trade publication is a nice change of pace as well). Even though these standards manual have already been the subject of much discussion, there’s so much that we miss out on when we focus on the design—in fact, the design might be one of the least important parts. If design is the method by which we give form to fictions, why would we examine only the form and not the fiction?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">I had previously read another one of Thomas De Monchaux’s pieces, “Have You Ever Had an Intense Experience of Mystical Communion with the Universe, Life, God, etc?” (also published in n+1) earlier last year. It was a review of a book on the life and work of architect Louis Kahn. That essay was one of the first essays I had read on architecture (I previously and foolishly tended to stay away from writings on architecture because I preferred to spend my time reading about graphic design), and the description of the field and the work made me realize exactly why designers today are so envious of the quality of dialogue architects and their critics are able to have.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“The Tears of Donald Knuth” by David A. Banks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/05/the-tears-of-donald-knuth-by-david-a-banks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“The Tears of Donald Knuth” by David A. Banks" /><published>2018-02-05T23:51:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-02-05T23:51:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/05/the-tears-of-donald-knuth-by-david-a-banks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/05/the-tears-of-donald-knuth-by-david-a-banks.html">&lt;p&gt;Reading this piece, I can’t help but to be reminded of a very eye-opening satirical talk of Bret Victor’s that I saw probably a few months ago called &lt;a href=&quot;http://worrydream.com/dbx/&quot;&gt;“The Future of Programming,”&lt;/a&gt; which plays on many of the same ideas explored here, although with a slightly different goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gist of the essay is this: Donald Knuth once read a paper called “The History of the History of Software” by computing historian Martin Campbell-Kelly which upset him so much as to move him not only to tears but also to deliver an impassioned speech titled “Let’s Not Dumb Down the History of Computing.” Knuth’s issue with the paper was that it remained mostly non-technical and therefore was not useful to computer scientists, who needed this history most of all. Banks uses the rest of this letter to explain why Knuth’s ire is deserved but misguided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Banks is concerned with pushing for more historians of computing in order to computer scientists’ understandings of the field, Victor in his talk makes the case for studying the history of computing (although really in his case it’s closer to the history of software) so that we might not become too settled into our understandings of what software is and might be. He cites the 1960s as an extremely fertile time in computer science, when the field was still so new that computer scientists had no idea what it was and so had no restrictions in their minds as to what it could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there’s much to be said about studying the history of human-computer interaction as well. I remember being in my HCI class sophomore year and being blown away by Douglas Engelbart’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Mother_of_All_Demos&quot;&gt;“Mother of All Demos,”&lt;/a&gt; in which he introduced to the world windows, the mouse, hypertext, video conferencing, and a collaborative text editor (among many things). So many of the things shown during that demonstrations are now commonplace in computers today and form the basis for our interface with computing. But why is our understanding of HCI so often defined in terms of these devices which have existed for almost 50 years?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been incredible explorations into novel forms of interaction. Richard Bolt created the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Pr2KIPQOKE&quot;&gt;Put-That-There&lt;/a&gt; system which used voice and gestures as the primary method for interaction with a computer which was an entire room (this idea of room-as-computer is something being explored in Victor’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://dynamicland.org&quot;&gt;Dynamicland&lt;/a&gt;, although as far as I know the similarities mostly end there).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this discussion around the value of studying history of a technical field is just another example of the contributions that the humanities can have toward the sciences. Some primary examples I can think of are Jeffrey Bardzell’s papers on HCI which brings in ideas from feminism, aesthetics, and critical theory. I’m also reminded of Mark Marino’s call for close readings of software in “Critical Code Studies” and Nick Monfort’s &lt;em&gt;10 Print,&lt;/em&gt; which manifests this practice. I hope, for Donald Knuth’s sake, that we get more historical writing that fits this bill too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Reading this piece, I can’t help but to be reminded of a very eye-opening satirical talk of Bret Victor’s that I saw probably a few months ago called “The Future of Programming,” which plays on many of the same ideas explored here, although with a slightly different goal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Engineered for Dystopia” by David A. Banks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/03/engineered-for-dystopia-by-david-a-banks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Engineered for Dystopia” by David A. Banks" /><published>2018-02-03T23:52:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-02-03T23:52:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/03/engineered-for-dystopia-by-david-a-banks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/03/engineered-for-dystopia-by-david-a-banks.html">&lt;p&gt;I often feel like I take issue with many of the same things about engineering that I do with design. Too often people push engineering as an objective endeavor (analogous to the design mantra “form follows function”), and so we are often fed a narrative that the systems built by engineers are somehow objective, just a solution to a problem. There’s also a general lack of critical discussion around engineering, which probably happens because for many of the same reasons as in design (e.g. the industry is often very closed-off, with the exception of open-source projects developed and maintained by these companies; the people who would be critiquing have obvious bias; most engineering does not lend itself to fruitful criticism; etc, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science, of course, is a field founded on critical inquiry. As we move further away from the practical and approach the theoretical, we come more and more into ideas which must be exhaustively proven before they are accepted. And while you can prove statements about engineering, these statements are typically proven through empirical evidence rather than, say, induction. That is, they must first and foremost demonstrate their utility, which makes sense in the context of engineering, but also seems to suggest that, like in design, it makes the practice of criticism less interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other thing I will say about engineering as far as its similarities to design goes is that we should not be surprised to often find that engineering is employed by people with power in devious ways. Engineers, like designers, are hired by wealthy people for their ability to create systems which help maintain the status quo. And especially in the age of software, the barrier to entry in this field is drastically low—all it takes is a laptop and an internet connection. This suggests that now, more than ever, is the time for us to be critical about the roles and responsibilities of engineers and how we should view their contributions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">I often feel like I take issue with many of the same things about engineering that I do with design. Too often people push engineering as an objective endeavor (analogous to the design mantra “form follows function”), and so we are often fed a narrative that the systems built by engineers are somehow objective, just a solution to a problem. There’s also a general lack of critical discussion around engineering, which probably happens because for many of the same reasons as in design (e.g. the industry is often very closed-off, with the exception of open-source projects developed and maintained by these companies; the people who would be critiquing have obvious bias; most engineering does not lend itself to fruitful criticism; etc, etc).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Cézzane’s Doubt” by Maurice Merleau-Ponty</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/25/c%C3%A9zzane-s-doubt-by-maurice-merleau-ponty.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Cézzane's Doubt” by Maurice Merleau-Ponty" /><published>2018-01-25T23:52:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-25T23:52:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/25/c%C3%A9zzane-s-doubt-by-maurice-merleau-ponty</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/25/c%C3%A9zzane-s-doubt-by-maurice-merleau-ponty.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Cézanne’s or Balzac’s artist is not satisfied to be a cultured animal but assimilates the culture down to its very foundations and gives it new structure: he speaks as the first man spoke and paints as if no one had ever painted before. What he expresses cannot, therefore, be the translation of a clearly defined thought, since such clear thoughts are those which have already been uttered by ourselves or by others. “Conception” cannot precede “execution.” There is nothing but a vague fever before the act of artistic expression, and only the work itself, completed and understood, is proof that there was &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; rather than &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to be said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above is a passage from “Cézzane’s Doubt” that made very clear to me an idea that had previously been very fuzzy in my head. We can compare the quote above with another one from Marcel Duchamp’s “The Creative Act,” which I read a few weeks ago:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To all appearances, the artist acts like a mediumistic being who, from the labyrinth beyond space and time, seeks his way out to a clearing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If we give the attributes of a medium to the artist, we must then deny him the state of consciousness on the esthetic plane about what he is doing or why he is doing it. All his decisions in the artistic execution of the work rest with pure intuition and cannot be translated into a self-analysis, spoken or written, or even thought out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I previously hadn’t really understood Duchamp’s statement because it wasn’t clear to me how an artist could make something without being aware of how he or she was making. I recognized that the idea of an artist as a medium was an interesting one to think about, but couldn’t grasp how it could actually be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That I wasn’t able to grasp this idea (which was first presented by an artist) firmly until it was repeated by a philosopher might be very fitting for the sentiment in these two statements. In any case, it’s a very useful way for thinking about the contributions of Cézanne, often referred to the father of modern art. When we think about the impact of Cézanne’s work and how it paved the way for an entire new way of thinking about art, it’s only reasonable that he was often troubled with an inability to express how he saw the world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Cézanne’s or Balzac’s artist is not satisfied to be a cultured animal but assimilates the culture down to its very foundations and gives it new structure: he speaks as the first man spoke and paints as if no one had ever painted before. What he expresses cannot, therefore, be the translation of a clearly defined thought, since such clear thoughts are those which have already been uttered by ourselves or by others. “Conception” cannot precede “execution.” There is nothing but a vague fever before the act of artistic expression, and only the work itself, completed and understood, is proof that there was something rather than nothing to be said.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Black to the Future: Interviews with Samuel A. Delany, Greg Tate, and Tricia Rose” by Mark Dery</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/23/black-to-the-future-interviews-with-samuel-a-delany-greg-tate-and-tricia-rose-by-mark-dery.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Black to the Future: Interviews with Samuel A. Delany, Greg Tate, and Tricia Rose” by Mark Dery" /><published>2018-01-23T23:52:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T23:52:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/23/black-to-the-future-interviews-with-samuel-a-delany-greg-tate-and-tricia-rose-by-mark-dery</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/23/black-to-the-future-interviews-with-samuel-a-delany-greg-tate-and-tricia-rose-by-mark-dery.html">&lt;p&gt;There’s an incredible amount of stuff to unpack from “Black to the Future,” Mark Dery’s seminal series of interviews in which he coined the term “Afrofuturism.” Most of the stuff here is pretty new to me—I’m by no means a sci-fi buff, so the majority of the work referenced in these conversations went over my head (that isn’t to say thought that there isn’t an incredible amount to learn, even if you aren’t familiar with a lot of sci-fi canon). As I read more, however, I started thinking about on Afrofuturist whose work did have a big impact on me: MF DOOM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that struck me about MF DOOM’s music when I first started listening to it some time ago in high school was just how different it sounded from anything I had heard before. This is a rapper who not only has an incredibly unique voice and flow but also raps over some of the most interesting production I’ve ever listened to. His samples come from a variety of sci-fi and fantasy sources, and feature snippets from the &lt;em&gt;Godzilla&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;The New Fantastic Four&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there’s something to be said for DOOM’s use of the villain persona (MF DOOM being an obvious play off of Dr. DOOM from the &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Four&lt;/em&gt; series, as well as his aliases King Geedorah, from &lt;em&gt;Godzilla&lt;/em&gt;, and Viktor Vaughn, another &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Four&lt;/em&gt; reference). He chooses these characters who present a very straightforward representation of good and evil, and under these names produces work which is of considerable merit. But for an evildoer to achieve recognition for his works does not make him famous, but rather infamous. DOOM acquires notoriety, just like the powerful characters from whom he takes his names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s also plenty of notoriety in the music industry already, especially in hip hop, which was born as a counterculture movement from people who had been historically oppressed huge entities which often seemed all-powerful. The gangsta rap music popular in the 80s and 90s celebrated its own villains, rappers who were former drug dealers and gangsters who developed plenty of notoriety and celebrity for their actions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">There’s an incredible amount of stuff to unpack from “Black to the Future,” Mark Dery’s seminal series of interviews in which he coined the term “Afrofuturism.” Most of the stuff here is pretty new to me—I’m by no means a sci-fi buff, so the majority of the work referenced in these conversations went over my head (that isn’t to say thought that there isn’t an incredible amount to learn, even if you aren’t familiar with a lot of sci-fi canon). As I read more, however, I started thinking about on Afrofuturist whose work did have a big impact on me: MF DOOM.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“On Self-Respect” by Joan Didion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/22/on-self-respect-by-joan-didion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“On Self-Respect” by Joan Didion" /><published>2018-01-22T01:06:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T01:06:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/22/on-self-respect-by-joan-didion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/22/on-self-respect-by-joan-didion.html">&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot to learn from this Joan Didion. Her famous essay on self-respect is well-known for good reason. It describes, in much better terms, something which many people have tried (and continue to try) to articulate, to varying degrees of success: that self-respect is, first and foremost, about loving and being comfortable enough with who you are to confront yourself. A lack of self-respect results in what Didion refers to as an “alienation from self:” we concern ourselves so much with the opinions of others that we lose any sense of identity. Without self-respect, we 	have nothing to base ourselves upon and so seek the validation of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t help but to feel a connection between the thesis in this essay and some of Jean-Paul Sartre’s work, especially his play &lt;em&gt;No Exit&lt;/em&gt; and his idea about the look. There are similar themes about the futility of living for other people and about recognizing your existence as beginning with &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, the subject, rather than &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, the object. To respect oneself is to stop justifying your existence to other people and being comfortable with being uncomfortable. It is not easy to achieve, but the discipline and fortitude required is a small price to pay when you consider the alternative.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">There’s a lot to learn from this Joan Didion. Her famous essay on self-respect is well-known for good reason. It describes, in much better terms, something which many people have tried (and continue to try) to articulate, to varying degrees of success: that self-respect is, first and foremost, about loving and being comfortable enough with who you are to confront yourself. A lack of self-respect results in what Didion refers to as an “alienation from self:” we concern ourselves so much with the opinions of others that we lose any sense of identity. Without self-respect, we have nothing to base ourselves upon and so seek the validation of others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Mindscapes” by Superstudio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/20/mindscapes-by-superstudio.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Mindscapes” by Superstudio" /><published>2018-01-20T01:06:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-20T01:06:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/20/mindscapes-by-superstudio</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/20/mindscapes-by-superstudio.html">&lt;p&gt;There’s a quote at the beginning of “Mindscapes” which touches on an idea that’s been echoed in past essays in this series:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And having for years interrogated the stars on the itinerary to follow, the navigator drew the constellations in the night…. 
Having for centuries interrogated the earth, the farmer drew geometric patterns on hills and valleys, transforming them into mosaics…. 
Finally, after examining the omens, the founder of the city drew a geometric perimeter on the ground and thereon he built the city….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these things—constellations, patterns for farms, city limits—are imposed upon the world. They are contrived. They have no right to exist, and they are neither correct or incorrect. These designs are our attempt to make order out of chaos, to control and manage some part of the environment around us. These things make so much sense to us, in fact, that we often forget that they are there. They seem almost as natural as the things they obscure. We look at a globe not remembering that there is no reason why it is placed with North at the top and South at the bottom, or why countries begin and end where they do. The grid, those lines marking latitudes and longitudes, are comforting in their rigidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the projects in “Mindscapes” almost seem like a caricature of those ideas: order and rigidity and grids blown up to huge scale, something straight out of a science fiction paperback. I’ve come to understand it as a piece of speculative design and a commentary of how unchecked, rampant design (a distinctly human trait) in the end causes us to lose our own humanity. When we look at these landscapes, we see massive, spanning structures which trace a perfect line to a distance focal point. They in many cases (&lt;em&gt;Logging Operation&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Niagara: The Reflected Architecture&lt;/em&gt;) literally dominate the natural world. To us, they stick out and seem unnatural. But will they always? Humans have a remarkable ability to adapt to new environments. Very rarely do we notice all the unnatural buildings and landscapes we live and operate in today. Technology changes rapidly, but we rapidly assimilate it into our lives, adopt it into our work and play.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">There’s a quote at the beginning of “Mindscapes” which touches on an idea that’s been echoed in past essays in this series:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“This is Not a Cigar: Rereading Rand” by Susan Sellers and Michael Rock</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/19/this-is-not-a-cigar-rereading-rand-by-susan-sellers-and-michael-rock.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“This is Not a Cigar: Rereading Rand” by Susan Sellers and Michael Rock" /><published>2018-01-19T01:05:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-19T01:05:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/19/this-is-not-a-cigar-rereading-rand-by-susan-sellers-and-michael-rock</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/19/this-is-not-a-cigar-rereading-rand-by-susan-sellers-and-michael-rock.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s not so often that you get see an example of design criticism as lucid and thoughtful as this. This reading of Rand’s work, which begins with an examination of a flyer Rand made for a brand of cigars, shows us just how ripe for examination graphic design can be, despite the fact that it often isn’t subjected to close readings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When reading about design, you often stumble onto people bemoaning the lack of criticism in the field (this was a big topic of conversation during the 90s especially. &lt;em&gt;Looking Closer 2&lt;/em&gt; has quite a number of essays devoted to talking about the various forms criticism might take). Graphic design is often compared to fields like architecture, art, and literature—all fields which involve not only the creation of artifacts but also the commentary on those artifacts by a trained critics. Even today, the question as to why we don’t have a similar culture of discourse around design (usually meaning graphic design in particular), continues to be asked in forums like Jarrett Fuller’s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scratchingthesurface.fm/post/166768970850/50-one-year-special-with-michael-bierut&quot;&gt;Scratching the Surface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of reasons that have been proposed as to why this lack of critical dialogue around design exists, but that’s left for designers to talk about. For me, a design dilettante, it’s nice to just be able to read an examination into the work of a graphic design icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This close reading of Rand’s work is a very insightful examination into the graphic devices deployed in order to make things appealing to men. While some have tried to separate design from its cultural context and present the goal of design as being a solution to a problem, design can only be successful if it is done with an intimate knowledge of culture (how people think, what people value) and that designed objects themselves have a tremendous impact on culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is Not a Cigar” invites us to look at these things which may seem innocuous at first (a flyer, a magazine), but which upon closer examination reveal that design’s foremost role is to materialize various fictions put forth on behalf of (often wealthy, often male, often white) people.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">It’s not so often that you get see an example of design criticism as lucid and thoughtful as this. This reading of Rand’s work, which begins with an examination of a flyer Rand made for a brand of cigars, shows us just how ripe for examination graphic design can be, despite the fact that it often isn’t subjected to close readings.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Research &amp;amp; Destroy: A Plea for Design as Research” by Daniel van der Velden</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/17/research-destroy-a-plea-for-design-as-research-by-daniel-van-der-velden.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Research &amp; Destroy: A Plea for Design as Research” by Daniel van der Velden" /><published>2018-01-17T18:21:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-17T18:21:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/17/research-destroy-a-plea-for-design-as-research-by-daniel-van-der-velden</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/17/research-destroy-a-plea-for-design-as-research-by-daniel-van-der-velden.html">&lt;p&gt;I must admit that I’ve never had a good understanding of what designers mean when they use the word “research” (e.g. as the title of Ellen Lupton’s book and former design studio, &lt;em&gt;Design, Writing, Research&lt;/em&gt; or in the title of this essay, “Research &amp;amp; Destroy: A Plea for Design as Research). I’m sure it differs from my understanding of the term, since my experience doing research is very traditionally scientific and academic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more importantly than the details of how research is done differently in the contexts of design vs. science, research almost seems like the antithesis of design. Research, as I have come to understand it, is about uncovering truths; design seems to be about legitimizing fictions (this idea on how form takes and loses meaning is also covered in previous essays in this series on objects and things). That is, design is the invention of things we take to be true in our culture. It is the source of all contrived truths. This is something I touched on briefly when I referenced Michael Rock’s Bloomberg Businessweek Design 2016 keynote in my last response to Karel Marten’s “What Does Design Mean to Me.” In his talk, Rock mentions design’s incredible power to make things in our world &lt;em&gt;coherent&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Design is a faith-based proposition. For design to work, we have to believe in it. And design is the physical manifestation of fiction, and those fictions are the fictions that we live our life by. So the purpose of design, when we ask, “what is design for?” I would say the purpose of design is to create coherent worlds, that coherence in itself is the function of design. And when you look at coherence, what is coherence? Coherence is to stick together, somehow to make something stick together. So the way we divide the world and make it stick together is the essence of what design does. Another way you could say that is that design projects our desire onto the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This statement really stuck with me when I first heard it. Design is the method through which we impose order on our lives. Design gives things value, meaning, and purpose. Daniel van der Velden echoes a very similar understanding: “Design is added value. En masse, designers throw themselves into desires instead of needs… Design only generates longing. The problem is the problem of luxury” (Jessica Helfand’s &lt;em&gt;Design: The Invention of Desire&lt;/em&gt; explores this idea even further). From this perspective, it becomes obvious as to why design plays such a huge role in commoditization and thus constraining and oppressing people rather than empowering them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;van der Velden also finds that designers themselves are becoming increasingly commodified, and spends a section of his essay on the degradation of the role of the designer as someone whose value comes from their ideas to someone who “holds a mouse and drags objects across a computer screen.” The solution suggested in “Research &amp;amp; Destroy” is for designers to turn to research: the designer needs to be valued for the knowledge they contribute rather than their labor. van der Velden is vague on what research means exactly in this context, but the result of it should be ”knowledge that makes it possible to seriously participate in discussions that are not about design.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an interesting proposition, but as to whether it would prevent designers from being used for their labor, I’m not so sure. I think the trend van der Velden is describing is extremely relevant today, and I have to say that it’s very apparent that the companies and institutions investing heavily in design today are most likely not hiring designers for their ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">I must admit that I’ve never had a good understanding of what designers mean when they use the word “research” (e.g. as the title of Ellen Lupton’s book and former design studio, Design, Writing, Research or in the title of this essay, “Research &amp;amp; Destroy: A Plea for Design as Research). I’m sure it differs from my understanding of the term, since my experience doing research is very traditionally scientific and academic.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“What Design Means to Me” by Karel Martens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/15/what-design-means-to-me-by-karel-martens.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“What Design Means to Me” by Karel Martens" /><published>2018-01-15T00:34:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-15T00:34:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/15/what-design-means-to-me-by-karel-martens</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/15/what-design-means-to-me-by-karel-martens.html">&lt;p&gt;Following up yesterday’s statement by designer Weiyi Li, this brief essay comes from one of her teachers at Yale, graphic designer Karel Martens. Here, Martens discusses how he has come to understand the role of design not only as a craft or a profession, but as an extension of himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His take on design is relatively straightforward. Having been brought up in the dogma of Modernism and (at time of writing) now living and designing during a time when those ideals were being so utterly rejected, he draws a middle ground between a completely functional view of design, where the designer’s opinions and beliefs are left out, and a completely expressive view of design, often at the expense of readability: what he refers to as “form about form.” He instead asks for a “form that values content and has respect for the receiver of the message.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to keep in mind what was going on in graphic design at the time. Martens wrote this in 1990, in the middle of what would later become know as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.printmag.com/typography/legibility-wars-translation-typography/&quot;&gt;“The Legibility Wars of the ‘80s and ‘90s.”&lt;/a&gt;, a period in graphic design history when new technology and changing attitudes among younger designers resulted in a clash between the old and new guard. Older designers were mostly still rooted in the Modernist, Swiss styles while younger designers were excited to explore everything that new technology made possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1984, Rudy VanderLans started publishing &lt;em&gt;Emigre&lt;/em&gt;, a graphic design magazine which was visually very divisive among designers for its exploration of eclectic type and bold, disruptive typography. Other publications, many founded by young students, started to eschew old rules of readability for the sake of expression. The second installment of the critical graphic design essay series, &lt;em&gt;Looking Closer 2&lt;/em&gt;, was published in 1997 and contains many essays on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear to see that this essay then is a product of the times, when this sort of debate was a hot topic in the design community. But I think what’s interesting about this is his rejection of content as having some sort of precedence over form. He says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The content of the message has to come over, but the way in which this happens—the melody—is important, not least because in itself it carries communicative value. It is through form that content comes to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a sentiment which has more recently been echoed by Michael Rock in his essay, &lt;a href=&quot;https://2x4.org/ideas/2/fuck-content/&quot;&gt;“Fuck Content”&lt;/a&gt; and his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/videos/2016-06-02/bloomberg-businessweek-design-2016-michael-rock&quot;&gt;opening keynote&lt;/a&gt; to Bloomberg Businessweek Design 2016, in which he advocates for the legitimacy of design in its own right. In Rock’s words, design makes things coherent. Things in the world become real by design—ideas are given form, ideologies given authority, humans given identity. Design is crucial to our understanding of the world and ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Following up yesterday’s statement by designer Weiyi Li, this brief essay comes from one of her teachers at Yale, graphic designer Karel Martens. Here, Martens discusses how he has come to understand the role of design not only as a craft or a profession, but as an extension of himself.</summary></entry></feed>